Nirmal Bhandari

Kashmir Road, London, SE7 8QN 07452879577 | Bhdnirmal99@gmail.com

A Third Year Computer Science undergraduate at the University of Surrey, who achieved high 2:1 in second year. With a year of experience as a full-stack developer, I am very good at problem solving, designing systems, and programming. On top of that, self-publishing while studying for A-levels as well as tutoring while holding a full-time job at a busy sandwich retailer has helped developed strong time management and organization skills. Given my experiences, I am also equipped with an ability to adapt to various environments.

Education and Qualifications

University of Surrey

2020-Present

B.Sc. Computer Science

Modules studied: Programming Fundamentals, Web and database, Foundation of Computing, Computer Logic, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Information System Management, Computational Intelligence, and Distributed Systems, Natural Language Processing, Advanced Web Technologies

Skills Acquired

- Programming using Java, Nodejs with Typescript, React, PHP, Docker, SQL, and MongoDB.
- Dividing problems into subproblems and representing them with class diagrams.
- Ability to manipulate data structures to write efficient algorithms.
- Working with cloud services such as Azure.
- Developing microservices application and deploying it on Azure Kubernetes Services.
- Creating CI/CD pipelines and using version control system, Git.

Thomas Tallis School

A level: Mathematics (A), Chemistry (B), Biology (C) 2019

Kemnal Technology College

GCSEs: 8 subjects, Mathematics (8) and English (4)

Employment

Royal Surrey NHS Foundation Trust Student Computer Scientist (Full-Stack Developer)

September 2022 – August 2023

- Designing, programming, and deploying scalable backend and frontend systems using Nodejs, PHP, and React.
- Designing and implementing database schema for relational and non-relational databases.
- Working with colleagues to produce efficient software solutions.
- Holding code review sessions to help find bugs in programs.

- Reviewing software with end users and implementing their feedback.
- Learning new technologies in-depth to ensure programs didn't have underlying bugs.

Mytutor.co.uk

July 2021 – April 2022

Tutor

- Analyzing student's weakness and planning lessons that help improve their abilities.
- Communicating ideas and concepts in a manner that leads to an understanding in the student.
- Documenting student's progress.
- Presenting a lesson efficiently and methodologically.
- Remaining patient and understanding of the student's behavior and their ability to learn.

Pret A Manger, Oxford Street, London

August 2021 - September 2021

Team Member

- Communicating effectively with customers and serving them in a professional and efficient manner in an environment that gets more than 100 customers per hour.
- Ensuring that the presentation of the products is up to standards.
- Communicating the needs of the customer to colleagues.
- Responsible for cleaning and stocking the shop when closing while considering the needs of the day after.

Self-Publishing Author

April 2018-Sep 2020

- Planning content and structuring the books while considering the interests of the readers.
- Ensuring the quality of product is up to customer standards.
- Designing a poster that represents the content of the books and relaying my needs to the artist.
- Negotiating prices with the editor and the artist for their services.
- Researching current popular genres and implementing the results into my writing which led to an increase in book sales of 156%.

Additional Skills

Languages: Fluent in English and Nepali. Understanding of Hindi.

References

Personal Tutor

Dr. Suparna De Lecturer University of Surrey s.de@surrey.ac.uk Manager

Mrs. Emma Lewis Principal Computer Scientist Royal Surrey NHS Foundation Trust emmalewis7@nhs.net